+234 817 719 0253 oayodavis@gmail.com LinkedIn

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To become an exceptional scientist and a renowned researcher in drug chemistry, ignite students' interest in the beauty of chemistry, mentor world class students and ultimately better the society through generation of science-based solutions to everyday problems.

RESEARCH INTEREST

Drug synthesis and design.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Chemistry: University of Ibadan, Nigeria (UI)

March 2015 - May 2019

CGPA: 5.3/7.0

A' level certificate: Global Cambridge College, Ibadan, Nigeria October 2013 - June 2014

13 points. Biology (B), Chemistry(B) and Physics(B)

Thesis: Phytochemical Investigation of the Stems of Tithonia Diversifolia (Hemsl) A. Gray. Link to abstract

Relevant Courses: Organic Chemistry, Organic and Physical Chemistry of Macromolecules, Heterocyclics, Carbocyclics and Reaction Mechanisms, Pericyclic reactions and Naturally Occurring Compounds, and Chemistry Seminar.

Seminar Topics:

- Application of Organic Compounds in Nanochemistry.
- Carbon Trading.
- Industrial Chemistry in Medicine.
- Inorganic Chemistry in Drug Design.
- Contribution of Chemistry towards Sustenance of Environmental Safety A review of Organic Chemosensors.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

National Reference Laboratory - Lab Technician

December 2020 - Present

 Part of the team of workers responsible for carrying out COVID-19 Tests on behalf of the Nigeria Center for Disease control NCDC

Raw Materials Research and Development Council - Research Assistant

July 2019 - March 2020

- Carried out expository research on numerous domestic raw materials which would enable government formulate appropriate policies for their exploitation, development, utilization and investment.
- Engaged in cluster programmes aimed at promoting value chain industrial development of the abundant locally available raw materials across the country.
- Compiled specifications for industrial chemicals and pharmaceutical raw materials
- Prepared periodic policy reports on all sectors as applicable to industrial chemicals and pharmaceutical industries.
- Collated and processed data on industrial chemicals and pharmaceuticals raw materials development and utilization.

Contact: Mr. C. K. Egbujor- egbujorchijioke@hotmail.com

oayodavis@gmail.com August 2018 - April 2019

Organic Laboratory, University of Ibadan - Undergraduate Research Assistant

- Compiled an in-depth literature review on Phytochemical Investigation of the Stems of Tithonia Diversifolia (Hemsl) A. Gray.
- Extracted and concentrated extracts from the stems of *Tithonia Diversifolia (Hemsl) A. Gray* in different solvents.
- Carried out bioassays and thin layer chromatography of extracts of the leaves and stems of *Tithonia* Diversifolia (Hemsl) A. Gray

Contact: Professor O. O. Aivelaagbe - oaivelaagbe@vahoo.com

Chemistry Department, University of Ibadan - Student

March 2015 - July 2018

- Carried out qualitative tests for salts, organic matter and effluents during weekly practical.
- Worked as part of a team in research laboratories

Contact: Professor T. I. Odiaka - timothy diaka@yahoo.co.uk

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

Nigerian Institute of Science Laboratory Technology-Intern

February - April 2018

- Chemical analysis on water samples (waste water, stream, rivers, streams) to establish whether water quality is within acceptable limits.
- Checks to determine whether levels of heavy metals and other pollutants in environmental samples are within regulatory guidelines.
- Preparation of required reagents used in chemical analysis.
- Sample preparation for chemical analysis.
- Visited industries to ensure their effluents were within regulatory guidelines.

Forestry Research Institute of Nigeria (FRIN)- Intern

December 2016 - February 2017

- Acquired further knowledge on the biological, chemical and physical properties of soils, and their spatial and temporal variability across the landscape
- Carried out field work, including the collection of soil samples from a range of environments
- Performed analysis on soil samples to check for the "plant available" organic content in them
- Evaluated the fertility status of soil samples from different parts of the country
- Carried out is the *in vitro* aseptic culture of cells, tissues, organs and whole plants under controlled nutritional and environmental conditions to produce the clones and varieties of plants.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Apo Junior Secondary School, Abuja- Maths and English Teacher

January 2020-March 2020

- Taught Junior Secondary Students English and Mathematics
- Prepared the students for their forthcoming exams

Government secondary school, Apo Resettlement, Abuja - Maths and English Teacher August - December 2019

- Taught Junior Secondary Students English and Mathematics
- Prepared students for later grades by encouraging them to explore learning opportunities and to persevere with challenging tasks.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Fundamentals of Manuscript Preparation - Elsevier Researcher Academy

August 2020

• Learned how to build well-articulated articles and using reference managers.

ACS Reviewer Lab December 2019

Learned the steps and important ethical considerations involved in peer review

+234 817 719 0253 <u>oayodavis@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

Introduction to Digital Humanities - HarvardX, edX

September - November 2019

• Learned digital research and visualization techniques across subjects and fields within the humanities

Introduction to Data Science - edX

September - October 2019

- Learned basic data exploration and visualization techniques in Microsoft Excel
- Learned Foundational statistics that can be used to analyze data

Fundamentals of Digital Marketing - Google

August 2019

Learned strategic marketing concepts and tools to address brand communication in a digital world

Project Management Program (PMP) – Dexter and Heros Consulting Ltd

August 2019-January 2020

• Established a solid foundation in project management, behaviors, skills, processes and tools.

Health, Safety and Environment (HSE) – Dexter and Heros Consulting Ltd

August 2019-January 2020

- Acquired knowledge, skills and solid training in the theories and practices of occupational health and safety, emergency planning and environmental management.
- Acquired training on the management, control and handling of all aspects of health, safety and environment in different work environment.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Federal Scholarship Board of Nigeria Scholarship Recipient
- Award of Meritorious Service, Students' Chemical Society of Nigeria.
- Award of Meritorious Service, Nnamdi Azikwe Hall
- Certificate of Appreciation, ENGINE

LEADERSHIP AND EXTRACURRICULARS

School Lead, Educating Nigerian Girls in New Enterprise (ENGINE)

August 2019- Present

- Participated in various programmes directed at improving learning outcomes and economic status of marginalized adolescent girls between the ages of 10 and 19 years in Abuja
- Provided life skills instruction to girls in the classroom.
- Provided Vocational and business skills training to girls in the classroom
- Engaged in activities to address barriers to girls' education (SHEro campaign, advocacy visits, social media campaigns, community engagements)

Volunteer, Red Cross

July 2019

 Volunteered as a Red Cross member in the National Youth Corps Training camp and learned the role of first responders in emergency situations

Team Member, Global Management Challenge, Nigeria.

May - June 2019

 Participated in a Business Management Simulation and finished with one of the highest Investment Performances in the school.

Volunteer, Ace5 Initiative

December 2018-July 2019

• Attended monthly orphanage visits and worked with other members in sourcing for funds and forming strategic partnerships with governmental and non-governmental organizations.

President, Student Chemical Society of Nigeria, University of Ibadan.

April 2018 - April 2019

- Processed correspondences for the society and served on numerous welfare committees.
- Exercised control, harmonized and coordinated different aspects of the society activities throughout the year
- Coordinated student council activities and was in charge of running student council meetings.
- Served as a direct representative of the student body to the department's administration
- Managed the society's budgets and was in charge of sourcing funds for capital projects

General Secretary, Nnamdi Azikwe Hall Electoral Committee

July 2018

Prepared agendas for meetings and kept records of the minutes of all meetings held

+234 817 719 0253 <u>oayodavis@gmail.com</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

- · Participated in the screening of nominees for all executive and legislative posts in the hall
- Exchanged correspondence with relevant school authorities to ensure legitimacy of the elections
- Checked voter eligibility, authenticated eligible voters, managed the electoral roll and was responsible for voter communication.
- Ensured the election process was legally watertight and announced the electoral results, and sent said results to relevant school authorities

WORKSHOPS & LECTURES

- International Conference and Expo on Drug Discovery, Designing and Development (Kano, Nigeria, 2020)
- Wood Expo Nigeria (Abuja, 2020)
- Inaugural Lecture, Professor J. A. O. Woods; Systematic Coordination Compounds: From Fundamentals to Applications (University of Ibadan, 2019).
- Global Leadership Summit, University of Ibadan
- Students' Chemical Society of Nigeria National Conference (Lautech, Ogbomoso, 2018)
- Chemical Society of Nigeria National Conference (University of Ibadan, Nigeria, 2018)

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Software and Programming: ChemDraw, MATLAB, Microsoft Office, HTML, CSS & Python.

Languages: English and Yoruba (native).

Interests and Hobbies: Data Science, Machine Learning, History, Philosophy, Chess, Foreign cultures, Politics, International relations.